In the previous video, we talked about Stochastic gradient descent, and how that can be much faster than Batch gradient descent.
在之前的视频中 我们讨论了随机梯度下降 以及它是怎样比批量梯度下降更快的
In this video, let's talk about another variation on these ideas is called Mini-batch gradient descent
在这次视频中 让我们讨论基于这些方法的另一种变形 叫做小批量梯度下降
they can work sometimes even a bit faster than stochastic gradient descent.
这种算法有时候甚至比随机梯度下降还要快一点
To summarize the algorithms we talked about so far.
首先来总结一下我们已经讨论过的算法
In Batch gradient descent we will use all m examples in each generation.
在批量梯度下降中每次迭代我们都要用所有的m个样本
Whereas in Stochastic gradient descent we will use a single example in each generation.
然而在随机梯度下降中每次迭代我们只用一个样本
What Mini-batch gradient descent does is somewhere in between.
小批量梯度下降做的介于它们之间
Specifically, with this algorithm we're going to use b examples in each iteration where b is a parameter called the "mini batch size"
准确地说 在这种方法中我们每次迭代使用b个样本 b是一个叫做"小批量规模"的参数
so the idea is that this is somewhat in-between Batch gradient descent and Stochastic gradient descent.
所以这种算法介于随机梯度下降和批量梯度下降之间
This is just like batch gradient descent, except that I'm going to use a much smaller batch size.
这就像批量梯度下降 只不过我会用小很多的批量规模
A typical choice for the value of b might be b equals 10, lets say, and a typical range really might be anywhere from b equals 2 up to b equals 100.
b的一个标准取值可能是10 比如说 b的一个标准的取值可能是2到100之间的任何一个数
So that will be a pretty typical range of values for the Mini-batch size.
因此那是小批量规模的一个非常典型的取值区间
And the idea is that rather than using one example at a time or m examples at a time we will use b examples at a time.
算法思想是我们每次用b个样本而不是每次用1个或者m个
So let me just write this out informally, we're going to get, let's say, b. For this example, let's say b equals 10.
所以让我正式地把它写出来 我们将要确定b 例如我们假设b是10
So we're going to get, the next 10 examples from my training set so that may be some set of examples xi, yi.
所以我们将要从训练集中取出接下来的10个样本 假设训练集是样本 (x(i).y(i)) 的集合
If it's 10 examples then the indexing will be up to x (i+9), y (i+9)
如果是10个样本 最多索引值达到(x(i+9),y(i+9))
so that's 10 examples altogether and then we'll perform essentially a gradient descent update using these 10 examples.
这是全部的10个样本 然后我们将要用这10个样本做一个实际上是梯度下降的更新
So, that's any rate times one tenth times sum over k equals i through i+9 of h subscript theta of x(k) minus y(k) times x(k)j.
因此 就是学习率乘以1/10乘以 k 对 h (x(k)-y(k))×x(k)j 从i到i+9求和
And so in this expression, where summing the gradient terms over my ten examples.
在这个表达式中 我们计算10个样本的梯度下降公式的和
So, that's number ten, that's, you know, my mini batch size and just i+9 again,
因此 这是数字10 就是小批量规模 i+9
the 9 comes from the choice of the parameter b, and then after this we will then increase, you know,
9来自参数b的选择 然后在这之后我们将要把 i 加10
i by tenth, we will go on to the next ten examples and then keep moving like this.
我们将要继续处理接下来的10个样本 然后像这样一直继续
So just to write out the entire algorithm in full.
因此完整地写出整个算法
In order to simplify the indexing for this one at the right top,
为了简化刚才的这个索引
I'm going to assume we have a mini-batch size of ten and a training set size of a thousand,
我将假设我有小批量规模为10和一个大小为1000的训练集
what we're going to do is have this sort of form, for i equals 1 and that in 21's the stepping,
我们接下来要做的就是计算这个形式的和 从i等于1、11、21等等开始
in steps of 10 because we look at 10 examples at a time.
步长是10因为我们每次处理10个样本
And then we perform this sort of gradient descent update using ten examples at a time
然后我们每次对10个样本使用这种梯度下降来更新
so this 10 and this i+9 those are consequence of having chosen my mini-batch to be ten.
所以这是10这是i+9 它们是小批量规模选取10带来的结果
And you know, this ultimate four-loop, this ends at 991 here because
这是最后的for循环 这里在991结束因为
if I have 1000 training samples then I need 100 steps of size 10 in order to get through my training set.
如果我有1000个训练样本那么为了遍历整个训练集我需要100个步长为10的循环
So this is mini-batch gradient descent.
这就是小批量梯度下降
Compared to batch gradient descent, this also allows us to make progress much faster.
相比批量梯度下降 这种算法也让我们进展快很多
So we have again our running example of, you know, U.S. Census data with 300 million training examples,
所以让我们再次处理美国3亿人的人口普查数据训练集
then what we're saying is after looking at just the first 10 examples we can start to make progress
然后我们要说的是在处理了前10个样本之后 我们可以开始优化参数θ
in improving the parameters theta so we don't need to scan through the entire training set.
因此我们不需要扫描整个训练集
We just need to look at the first 10 examples and this will start letting us make progress and then
我们只要处理前10个样本然后这可以让我们有所改进
we can look at the second ten examples and modify the parameters a little bit again and so on.
接着我们可以处理第二组10个样本 再次对参数做一点改进 然后接着这样做
So, that is why Mini-batch gradient descent can be faster than batch gradient descent.
因此 这就是小批量梯度下降比批量梯度下降快的原因
Namely, you can start making progress in modifying the parameters after looking at just ten examples
你可以在只处理了10个样本之后就改进参数
rather than needing to wait 'till you've scan through every single training example of 300 million of them.
而不是需要等到你扫描完3亿个样本中的每一个
So, how about Mini-batch gradient descent versus Stochastic gradient descent.
那么 小批量梯度下降和随机梯度下降比较又怎么样呢？
So, why do we want to look at b examples at a time rather than look at just a single example at a time as the Stochastic gradient descent?
也就是说 为什么我们想要每次处理b个样本 而不是像随机梯度下降一样每次处理一个样本？
The answer is in vectorization.
答案是——向量化！
In particular, Mini-batch gradient descent is likely to outperform Stochastic gradient descent
具体来说 小批量梯度下降可能比随机梯度下降好
only if you have a good vectorized implementation.
仅当你有好的向量化实现时
In that case, the sum over 10 examples can be performed in a more vectorized way
在那种情况下 10个样本求和可以用一种更向量化的方法实现
which will allow you to partially parallelize your computation over the ten examples.
允许你部分并行计算10个样本的和
So, in other words, by using appropriate vectorization to compute the rest of the terms,
因此 换句话说 使用正确的向量化方法计算剩下的项
you can sometimes partially use the good numerical algebra libraries and parallelize your gradient computations over the b examples,
你有时可以使用好的数值代数库来部分地并行计算b个样本
whereas if you were looking at just a single example of time with Stochastic gradient descent then, you know,
然而如果你是用随机梯度下降每次只处理一个样本 那么你知道
just looking at one example at a time their isn't much to parallelize over.
每次只处理一个样本没有太多的并行计算
At least there is less to parallelize over.
至少并行计算更少
One disadvantage of Mini-batch gradient descent is that there is now this extra parameter b,
小批量梯度下降的一个缺点是有一个额外的参数b
the Mini-batch size which you may have to fiddle with, and which may therefore take time.
你需要调试小批量大小 因此会需要一些时间
But if you have a good vectorized implementation this can sometimes run even faster that Stochastic gradient descent.
但是如果你有一个好的向量化实现这种方法有时甚至比随机梯度下降更快
So that was Mini-batch gradient descent which is an algorithm that in some sense does something
好了 这就是小批量梯度下降算法
that's somewhat in between what Stochastic gradient descent does and what Batch gradient descent does.
在某种意义上做的事情介于随机梯度下降和批量梯度下降之间
And if you choose their reasonable value of b. I usually use b equals 10, but,
如果你选择合理的b的值 我经常选择b等于10 但是
you know, other values, anywhere from say 2 to 100, would be reasonably common.
你知道 别的值 比如2到100之间的任何一个数都可能合理
So we choose value of b and if you use a good vectorized implementation,
因此我们选择b的值 如果你有一个好的向量化实现
sometimes it can be faster than both Stochastic gradient descent and faster than Batch gradient descent.
有时它可以比随机梯度下降和批量梯度下降更快 【教育无边界字幕组】翻译: zearom32 校对/审核: 所罗门捷列夫